Maria's dangerous symptoms were controlled, and she delivered a healthy baby girl. And before Maria was discharged from the hospital, her doctor counseled her again about the signs and symptoms of preeclampsia, the importance of having her blood pressure checked, especially in this first week postpartum and gave her education about postpartum health and what to expect. And in the weeks and months that followed, naturally, Maria had follow-up visits with her pediatrician to check in on her baby's health. But just as important, she had follow-up visits with her ob-gyn to check in on her health, her blood pressure, and her cares and concerns as a new mother. This is what high-quality care across the care continuum looks like, and this is how it can look. If every pregnant woman in every community received this kind of high-quality care and delivered at facilities that utilized standard care practices, our maternal mortality and severe maternal morbidity rates would plummet. Our international ranking would no longer be an embarrassment. But the truth is, we've had decades of unacceptably high rates of maternal death and life-threatening complications during delivery and decades of devastating consequences for moms, babies and families, and we have not been moved to action. The recent media attention on our poor performance on maternal mortality has helped the public to understand: high-quality maternal health care is within reach. The question is: Are we as a society ready to value pregnant women from every community? For my part, I'm doing everything I can to ensure that when we do, we have the tools and evidence base ready to move forward. Thank you. (Applause)
Sus peligrosos síntomas fueron controlados y María tuvo una niña sana. Y, antes de darle el alta del hospital, su médico la asesoró nuevamente sobre los signos y síntomas de la preeclampsia, la importancia de hacerse controlar la presión, especialmente en la primera semana de postparto, y la educó sobre la salud después del parto y sobre qué debía esperar. Durante las siguientes semanas y meses, María tuvo visitas de seguimiento con su pediatra para que controlara la salud de su niña. Pero, igualmente importante, tuvo visitas continuas con su ginecólogo para controlar su salud, su presión sanguínea y sus precauciones y preocupaciones como madre primeriza. Este es el aspecto de una atención de calidad en el espectro de atención y así debería ser. Si cada embarazada de cada comunidad recibiera este tipo de atención de calidad y diera a luz en sitios que utilicen prácticas de atención estándares, nuestras tasas de mortalidad y morbilidad maternas extremas se desplomarían. Nuestro posicionamiento en el mundo ya no sería una vergüenza. Pero la verdad es que hemos tenido décadas de altos índices, inaceptables, de muerte materna y complicaciones potencialmente mortales durante el parto y décadas de consecuencias devastadoras para las mamás, los bebés y las familias, y no hemos hecho nada. La atención reciente de los medios al mal desempeño con la mortalidad materna ayudó para que la gente comprendiera que la atención materna de calidad está a nuestro alcance. La cuestión es: ¿Estamos listos como sociedad a valorar a las embarazadas de cada comunidad? Por mi parte, hago todo lo que puedo para asegurarnos de que cuando lo hacemos, tengamos las herramientas y la base empírica listas para avanzar. Gracias. (Aplausos)